Guide to the Peter Ackroyd Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- September 2010 Acquisition, 1989-2008; Series XV; 17.09 linear feet (21 boxes, including 21 computer disks and 1 laptop computer)
  Purchased from R. A. Gekoski, on the Edwin J. Beinecke Book Fund, 2010.
  Former call number: Uncat MSS 1262.
  Organized under four headings: Writings, Personal Papers, Correspondence, and Audiovisual Materials.
  This acquisition consists of writings, including Canterbury Tales, English Ghost, The Life of Thomas More, Pit and the Pendulum, Thames, Venice, and other works; correspondence; and audiovisual materials.
  - Writings
    - Albion: the Origins of the English Imagination, 2001 Sep 21; 5 (Box 108)
    - An Afternoon with Peter Ackroyd, 1997-1998 (Box 108)
    - And That's True Too or Shakespeare, 4 (Box 108)
    - Architetture Postmoderne I palinsesti di Peter Ackroyd (Box 108)
    - Book jackets (Box 108)
    - Brief Guide to Shakespeare (Box 108)
    - The Canterbury Tales: a Retelling, 2008; 4 (Box 108)
    - The Canterbury Tales: a Retelling, 2008; 9 (Box 109)
    - Casebook of Victor Frankenstein, notebooks I-VIII, 8 (Box 109)
    - Casebook of Victor Frankenstein, proofs, 2008 Jun 24; 2 (Box 110)
    - Casebook of Victor Frankenstein, 3 (Box 110)
    - Clerkenwell Tales, poster
    - Culture II (Box 110)
    - Dan Leno and the Limehouse Golem, adapted by Jack Bradley from the novel by Peter Ackroyd, 2003 Apr 8 (Box 110)
    - English Ghost, 4 (Box 110)
    - Englishness of English Literature: A Six-Part Series (Box 110)
    - The Fall of Troy - N.B. Poe I/II Notes, 2 (Box 110)
    - The Fall of Troy - N.B. Poe I/II Notes, 2 (Box 111)
    - The Fall of Troy (Box 111)
    - Futter, Stephen - Conjuring Tricks and Balancing Acts: The Fiction of Peter Ackroyd, 1994 Jan (Box 111)
    - Gallix, François - English Music by Peter Ackroyd. (Box 111)
    - Golen de Lonares Peter Ackroyd (Box 111)
    - Labayen, Maria Jose Auria - Hawksmoor y First Light, 1995 (Box 111)
    - Hawksmoor, screenplay by Kevin Hood - 4th-5th drafts, 2 (Box 111)
    - Hawksmoor, screenplay by Christopher Wicking - 2nd-4th drafts, 3 folders (Box 111)
    - History of England in Six Volumes, 2 (Box 111)
    - History of the English Imagination; Lectures; London & Poe (Box 111)
    - History III (Box 111)
    - House of Doctor Dee, screenplay by Mike Stephenson, 2002 (Box 111)
    - Index Cards A-C (Box 111)
    - Index Cards C-Z (Box 112)
    - King Arthur and the Holy Grail, 4 (Box 112)
    - Last Testament of Oscar Wilde, contract, 2006 (Box 112)
    - London Destination film - second draft, 1999 Jun 28 (Box 112)
    - London Lectures - Articles About London, 4 (Box 112)
    - Malory, 5 (Box 112)
    - Merlin, 2 (Box 113)
    - Merritt, Steph - Pastiche, Intertextuality and Tradition in the Novels of Peter Ackroyd (Box 113)
    - Millington, Jeannette - Analysing Ackroyd, 1992 (Box 113)
    - Miscellaneous, 5 (Box 113)
    - The Life of Thomas More, 9 (Box 113)
    - The Life of Thomas More, 7 (Box 114)
    - Newton, Sir Isaac - flash cards (Box 114)
    - Notebook, 7 (Box 114)
    - Parody and Pastiche in Modernism and Postmodernism with specific reference to Ulysses and the works of Peter Ackroyd (Box 114)
    - Pit and the Pendulum - proofs, 2008 Nov 12; 2 (Box 114)
    - Pit and the Pendulum (Box 114)
    - Plato Papers (Box 114)
    - Poe and Shakespeare (Box 114)
    - Potter, Dylan Joshua - Dunstan's Trident (Box 114)
    - Research material, 3 (Box 114)
    - Reviews (Box 114)
    - Reviews, 13 (Box 115)
    - Reviews by Peter Ackroyd, 6 (Box 115)
    - The Shakespeares, 2 (Box 116)
    - Shakespeare XVII, 5 (Box 116)
    - Shakespeare XVIII, 4 (Box 116)
    - Shakespeare XIX, 4 (Box 116)
    - [Shakespeare], 5 (Box 116)
    - Table talk by Peter Ackroyd (Box 116)
    - Thames: Sacred River, 2007; 17 (Box 117)
    - Thames: Sacred River, 4 folders, including 2 computer disks (Box 118)
      Uncat MSS 1262 Disk #1: Clive Boursnell lo-res jpegs Covent Garden, 2007
      Uncat MSS 1262 Disk #2: Clive Boursnell Covent Garden photos 1969-74
    - Thames: Sacred River
    - Thames: Sacred River contract, 2007 (Box 118)
    - Van den Bergh, Tania - Postmodern Plagiarism and the Transcendence of Time, 1989 Jun (Box 118)
    - Venice: Pure City
      - Miscellaneous, 3 (Box 118)
      - Setting Copy (Box 118)
      - Miscellaneous, 3 (Box 118)
      - Venice/Poe, 4 (Box 118)
      - I, 5 (Box 119)
      - II, 4 (Box 119)
      - III, 4 (Box 119)
      - IV, 5 (Box 119)
      - V, 4 (Box 120)
      - VI, 5 (Box 120)
      - VII, 4 (Box 120)
      - VIII, 4 (Box 120)
      - IX, 4 (Box 121)
      - X, 4 (Box 121)
    - Miscellaneous, 8 (Box 121)
  - Personal papers, 1987-2006
    - American Academy of Arts and Sciences certificate, 2006
    - Brunel University degree, 2006 Jul 19 (Box 122)
      Related Archival Materials note
      See also: Brunel University: West London - Graduation Ceremony, DVD in Box 125.
    - Brunel University - Degree Congregations and Award Ceremonies, booklet, 2005 Jul (Box 122)
    - Brunel University - photographs., 2005
    - Appointment book, 2005 (Box 122)
    - Appointment book, papers, photographs, 1993; 3 (Box 122)
    - Appointment book, 2006 (Box 122)
    - Financial papers
      - Bills, 2 (Box 122)
      - Checkbook (Box 122)
      - Contracts (Box 122)
    - Kuhn, Brian Michael
      - Correspondence, 1988-1993 (Box 122)
      - Miscellaneous, 1974-1996 (Box 122)
      - Passport, 1993 (Box 122)
      - Statements, 1987-1994 (Box 122)
    - Medical (Box 122)
      Includes x-rays of Ackroyd's knee
    - Miscellaneous (Box 122)
    - Photographs, 2 (Box 122)
    - Printed material (Box 122)
    - Receipts, 4 (Box 122)
    - Reviews, letters, miscellaneous, 2 (Box 122)
    - Reviews, letters, miscellaneous, 3 (Box 123)
    - Statements (Box 123)
    - Travel (Box 123)
    - Miscellaneous computer disks, 15 computer disks and 1 laptop computer
      Computer disks and laptop computer are restricted. Reference copies of electronic files may be requested through Access Services.
      Uncat MSS 1262 Disks #3-7: untitled
      Uncat MSS 1262 Disk #8: "WS interview" 26/9/05
      Uncat MSS 1262 Disk #9: Underground River Embryonic Heraldry - conduit 01-CD
      Uncat MSS 1262 Disk #10: untitled
      Uncat MSS 1262 Disk #11: "Building Britain: London," presented by Peter Ackroyd, 2007
      Uncat MSS 1262 Disk #12: Palma New Year/The Royal Progress/Dame Petra/Princess of R.
      Uncat MSS 1262 Disk #13 The Canterbury Tales BBC Radio Kent, 10/4/09
      Uncat MSS 1262 Disk #14: Shakespeare-IllusSectPDFs
      Uncat MSS 1262 Disk #15: Thames
      Uncat MSS 1262 Disk #16: untitled 3.11.08
      Uncat MSS 1262 Disk #17: MS Office 2003; files may not be requested.
      Uncat MSS 1262 Disk #18: untitled
      Uncat MSS 1262 Disk #19: Eeeeer...we go! Selotape, T-Shirt and bloodied knife!?
      Uncat MSS 1262 Disk #20: Celia Lowenstein
      Uncat MSS 1262 Disk #21: The Oxford English Dictionary Second Edition on Compact Disc, 1992; files may not be requested.
      Uncat MSS 1262 Laptop computer: Apple Powerbook Duo 230
  - Correspondence
    - Letters [unsorted], 1987-2008; 15 (Box 124)
  - Audiovisual Materials
    Access to original audiovisual recordings is restricted. Reference copies may be requested through Access Services.
    - Brunel University, West London - Graduation Ceremony, DVD, 2006 Jul 19 (Box 125)
      Box 125 (audiovisual material): Access to original audiovisual recordings is restricted. Reference copies may be requested through Access Services.
    - "The Fiery World by Peter Ackroyd" - listening master, two audio compact discs (Box 125)
    - Three 7-inch 45 rpm phonodisc recordings, 1962-1963 (Box 125)
      Includes: "Scotch Brew" by The Earthworms (recorded December 29, 1962), "Snow in the Frying Pan" by The Earthworms (recorded January 2, 1963, and "Macbeth Unchained" by The Earthworms (recorded January 2, 1963).
    - Miscellaneous DVDs (Box 125)
      Includes: The Book Show, Series 4, Episode #12, New Anthology: English Chapter (Russian), London Visions with Peter Ackroyd, Episodes #1-4, Peter Ackroyd's Venice: Disk One, and Peter Ackroyd's Venice: Disk Two.
  - Oversize
    - Miscellaneous oversize items from boxes above (Box 126)
  - Computer media
    - Computer disks
      - Lo-res jpegs Covent Garden ©2007 Clive Boursnell copied for Peter Ackroyd 19-9-07, 2010-genm-38821-0001; 1 (Box 127)
        Restricted fragile material. Access copies of digital files may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
      - 61 images lo-res watermarked © market Photos Ltd 2006 Clive Boursnell Covent Garden Photos 1969-74, 2010-genm-38821-0002; 1 (Box 127)
      - [no label information], 2010-genm-38821-0003; 1 (Box 127)
      - CONFIDENTIAL ADV. COPY 26/9/05 18:22 "WS INTERVIEW" © OTB PRODS 2005, 2010-genm-38821-0004; 1 (Box 127)
      - THE UNDERGROUND RIVER CONDUIT 01-CD ADVANCE COPY 26/50, 2010-genm-38821-0005; 1 (Box 127)
      - [no label information], 2010-genm-38821-0006; 1 (Box 127)
      - Building Britain: London Presented by Peter Ackroyd Produced & Directed by Celia Lowenstein, 2010-genm-38821-0007; 1 (Box 127)
      - PALOMA NEW YEAR. THE ROYAL PROGRESS DAME PETRA PRINCESS OF R., 2010-genm-38821-0008; 1 (Box 127)
      - The Canterbury Tales BBC Radio Kent TX: 10/4/09, 2010-genm-38821-0009; 1 (Box 127)
      - SHAKESPEARE - ILLUST PDFs., 2010-genm-38821-0010; 1 (Box 127)
      - [no label information], 2010-genm-38821-0011; 1 (Box 127)
        Restricted fragile material. Access copies of digital files may be requested.
        Consult Access Services for further information.
      - 3.11.08, 2010-genm-38821-0012; 1 (Box 127)
      - MS OFFICE 2003, 2010-genm-38821-0013; 1 (Box 127)
      - Ackroyd nip [illegible word], 2010-genm-38821-0014; 1 (Box 127)
      - Eeeeer…we go! Selotape, T-Shirt and bloodied knife!? Oh…and a couple of cunts!, 2010-genm-38821-0015; 1 (Box 127)
      - Celia Lowenstein, 2010-genm-38821-0016; 1 (Box 127)
      - The Oxford English Dictionary Second Edition on Compact Disc, 2010-genm-38821-0017; 1 (Box 127)
    - Laptop computer: Apple Powerbook Duo 230, circa 1994 (Box 128)